Guide to the George A. Romero Archival Collection, 1962-2017 SC.2019.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Photographs, circa 1950s-2017; VII.
  - Photo Album with stills from various projects, circa 1968-1985; 61 Photographic Prints (Oversize 102, Item 2)
  - Copperhead Conquers the Warhawks artwork designs, 1983; 36 Photographic Slides (Box 101, Folder 21)
    Slides of proposed artwork for the unproduced project in association with Marvel Comics Copperhead Conquers the Warhawks.
  - School Photograph, circa 1956-59; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 101, Folder 22)
  - Romero with his first camera, circa 1963; 2 Photographic Prints (Box 101, Folder 23)
  - Publicity Headshots, circa 1976; 25 Photographic Prints (Box 101, Folder 24)
  - Romero at Internationale Hofer Filmtage, circa October 1978; 9 Photographic Prints (Box 101, Folder 25)
    Photos of Romero at the Internationale Hofer Filmtage held in Hof, Bavaria, Germany on October 26-29, 1978 at which Dawn of the Dead was shown. Includes photo of Romero with Dario Argento.
  - Contact sheets with stills from an interview or documentary, 1981; 4 Sheets (Box 101, Folder 26)
  - George A. Romero and Stephen King, 1982; 2 Photographic Prints (Box 101, Folder 27)
  - Early Photographs of Romero, circa 1960s-1980s; 24 Photographic Prints (Box 101, Folder 28)
  - Later photos of Romero, circa 2010s; 5 Photographic Prints (Box 101, Folder 29)
- Moving Image Media (forthcoming), VIII.
- Props and Realia (in-progress), circa 1983-2017; IX.
  The series contains props from film sets and realia. NOTE: ALL ITEMS IN THIS SERIES ARE CURRENTLY ON DISPLAY IN THE HILLMAN LIBRARY ARCHIVES & SPECIAL COLLECTIONS EXHIBITION GALLERY.
  - Film Props, circa 1983-2006; 1.
    This subseries contains props from film sets.
    - Copy of The Southern Globe from July 9, 1984 with the headline "The Dead Walk!", circa 1983-85
      From the film Day of the Dead (1985). Can be seen on the ground during the opening sequence of a post-zombie apocalyse Fort Myers, Florida.
    - Ella the Monkey, circa 1986-88
      From the film Monkey Shines (1988) made by Tom Savini from plastic, polyurethane foam, and synthetic hair. While live monkeys were used for much of the film, several props were constructed for scenes that would be too dangerous for a live animal.
    - The Writer's Quill Award for Best Short Story awarded on April 20, 1985 to Thaddeus Beaumont, circa 1990-1993
      From the film The Dark Half (1993) can be seen hanging on the wall of the campus office of Professor Beaumont (played by Timothy Hutton).
    - People Magazine article "The Dear Departed Was Extremely Close To These Two People So Why Are They Laughing?", circa 1990-1993
      From the film The Dark Half (1993). Mockup of People Magazine article featuring Thad and Liz Beaumont (played by Timothy Hutton and Amy Madigan). The article features centers on the decision to 'bury' Beaumont's pseudonym George Stark after the pen name was exposed.
    - Plasticine masks, circa 1999-2000; 3 items
      From the film Bruiser (2000). Masks worn by main character Henry Creedlow (played by Jason Flemyng). Set of 3 masks: 2 with red teardrop markings; 1 cracked in half.
    - Crossbow with quiver and bolts, circa 2004-2005
      From the film Land of the Dead (2005). Weapons used by main character Cholo DeMora (played by John Leguizamo).
    - ID Badge, circa 2004-2005
      From the film Land of the Dead (1985) used by Charlie (played by Robert Joy).
  - Realia (in-progress), circa 2010-2017; 2.
    - Zombie head, date unknown
      Latex zombie head given to Romero at at convention circa 2010. Provenence, artist, or project unknown.
    - Hollywood Walk of Fame Star Plaque, October 25, 2017
      Plaque commemorating the dedication of a Hollywood Walk of Fame Star to George A. Romero.